Hey guys, welcome to the session, so before jumping out to the process threads or the
dealers, you need to learn few things before the PE, so PE is basically called us a portable
executeable. So let us take a Windows based applications, so it will be the Windows based
application will be in the EXE format or in like EXE executable format. So we will call
that as for PE, portable executeable, chrome.exe, so let us see an example how we are operating
a load that program, so let us take a hard disk, okay, honestly what storage system you
need, you can take that. So here in the folder, there is a chrome.exe, right, so when
you double click on the chrome.exe, the windows have their own loader PE loader, portable
executeable loader, this loader will take the chrome.exe from the disk, from the hard disk
from our directory, so the directory is like whether you have downloaded and the C uses
our downloads or any other directory, so it will load the chrome.exe from the directory
into the memory, okay, so memory means of SQL memory like RAM, okay RAM, CPU or whatever
you can call, okay, so this is the normal process when you are executing any program, the
program will be loaded in the from disk to the memory of the CPU, okay, so this is the normal
process but the PE, executeable will see some headers, like we will see that it depends
upon you if you want to learn, you can, if you want to skip, you can go ahead and skip
that topics because you need to understand this kind of topics in a malware analysis, okay,
so let's see a real example, let me, so this is the program which we have created yesterday,
let's pull the PE beer, so PE beer is an application used for malware analysis, like
using the executeable, we can understand what are the functions, APAs and libraries were used,
this open source application you can download it from the Google easily, not a complicated
thing, nothing you are going to pay anything for this, okay, so when you are downloading
for Windows, you can, you can see this releases, sorry, yep, you can see here download
the latest release, so click on that and you can download whatever version you want,
I better go for a latest version, so if you are making the, making download, okay, so this
is the PE beer, this tool is used for malware analysis, the static analysis, so here you
can see the load PE's, so let's load our program which we have created yesterday, robust
circuit, so now you can see there is much data get loaded inside the PE beer, so you can
see the header, header information, dos, header, okay, so dos is a one of the operating
system, this program will not load in the dos mode, okay, that's previously we used the
operating system, so there is a empty header, signature headers and a lot of headers we have,
and we have a text section, so text section contains the code which needs to execute basically,
and the data section and we hear resource sections, right, so our data sessions and so this
kind of section will hold the information like icons and the icon of the program or whatever
extra things we are giving, it will hold the information and text section will contain
the program that we need to execute, these are the separate separate section, right,
but when we developed the program we didn't care about any, we didn't set any session
header or any file headers, but when we compiled the program, when you are compiling the
program you are changing your program into EXE format, your compiler will set or will all
will do all these things, okay, it will do all these things, it's an automated, it will
do all these things, you don't need to do anything like manually pointing the session header
or option header all done, okay, so this is called as the PE, the PE files contains many
headers, headers, information like functions, instead of header information you can see
the APA functions, whatever things which can be used, okay, so I already said the text
header contained the program which we have already can see the program here, CMD.exe and
library files which we have which we have developed and all, okay, so let's start this,
let's go to the NT header, you can see the first two values of the file, you can see
it's a PE portable executable, if you going to the desk header you can see the magic value
of 4D and 5A and it was pointing to the image set, so if you want more clear about that,
so we can say that as a magic value like 4D5A file header, so this file header basically
says it's an EXE files, executable files, so this is called as the magic number, so if you
will be the mark to something something, okay, so it's a M is an executable file format used
for EXE files, okay, basically this is the extension for EXE dot com or dot dl files, okay,
so now you have a clear understanding about the PE loaders and process executable, how
the PE loader will take the EXE from the disk and it will execute load into the memory
and how to identify whether the file was executed or file or not, okay, if I load some
other file let it unload it and let's load some other files if we have, let's load this
bad file, so the bad file will not be get loaded, so let's try to load some other files from
the disk, leave that leave the alerts, okay, let's skip that, so if you pull any other files
into the PE, the form header format will be changed, okay, it will be, it will, it did not
in the M is that our PE, it will be in the other magic values, okay, so let's come through
our discussion, what is the process and what is the thread, so I have put a simple presentation
for this, but this, we will see the things in a practical if you, if you are just reading
this, you will not able to understand what is the process and what is the thread, okay,
so let's jump on to the Canva, so what is the process many of you seeing the process is
called as a application, so process is called as a Chrome or whatever you want, but the
technical term is process, you can say it's a container, okay, the process is a container,
this container contains information about the DLLs library files, PE programs, the code
of the executable and we have an API's, imports exports, many, many, many things are
there, we already see the, the headers information say everything, right, it will be called
as a process, okay, a process a container which hold every information like this, the DLL
is everything it will hold instead the container, okay, that's called as a process, okay,
so if you take an example of a process which the process has a separate ID, so let's see
that, let's install the process attacker, so you can see the PID of the process, the
SC shows holding the 940 and task was 988, each process hold a separate PID process ID,
it has a process ID, okay, so let's take one of the process, I'll give something, yeah,
let's take a notepad.exe, let's double click on that, let's explore the notepad, so now
you can see the threads and modules, memory, environment, DLLs get load on these are the files
get loaded and you can see the DLL files here, the APP help the DLL a lot of things,
this is called as the process, okay, so it has a thread, it has a token information so
which privilege it has and the modules which DLLs get loaded and the memory information,
the environment TV process environment block, a lot of things will be there, okay, so this
is called as the process, okay, let's take an example of a thread, so what is a thread,
so thread is an execution object of a program, okay, so let's take an example of
chrome.exe, so this chrome.exe need to do multiple functionalities like, right, so
like need to connect to internet, internet, need to download, upload, this process has multiple
functionalities, right, thread is an execution object of a program, okay, when you called
the download, if you try to download something, there is a one thread will be loaded, okay,
or like download, okay, the name is a download, the thread will be loaded and it will do
their function, it's an execution object, okay, the process contain one or more thread,
okay, based on the process functionality, the process contain one or more thread, okay,
so need to develop a program, right, so that program basically contain many threads, right,
so it need to provide a C2C and execute our command, so this all the things are doing
by the thread, separate, separate, don't buy one thread, okay, so if there is a need to connect
to the internet, there is one thread will be loaded, need to download one thread will be
loaded, need to upload another one thread will be loaded, so this is called as the thread, okay, it's an
execution object of a program, so one process contains more or one or more than one thread, okay,
so in the notepad, you can see a thread here, so you can see there is a four thread will be loaded,
right, so every process contain one or more than one thread, okay, so this is called as the process
and a thread, I hope you have a clear understanding about this video, let's hope of this video
and we will continue our discussion in the next video, see you guys bye-bye!